

JITENDRA AGRAWAL

- +919509555862
- jitendra.x.agrawal@hotmail.com
- Jaipur, 302021

CORE SKILLS

- Testing Technology: QA, Automation Testing, Manual Testing, DB Testing
- Automation Tools: Cucumber, Selenium, Jmeter, QTP, Eclipse
- API Testing Tool: Postman, WCF Test Client, IE Tester
- Defect Tracking Tools: JIRA, Azure DevOps, BugNET, Backlog, Bugzilla, Quality Centre10, ITS
- Programming Language: Core java,
 SQL

CERTIFICATIONS

- Software Testing Certification from ISTQB (UK).
- **Software Testing** Certification from STQAC, Pune.

EDUCATION

2009

Seed Infotech Ltd | Pune, MH Diploma: Software Testing

2008

Amdocs India Pvt Ltd | Pune, MH Trainee: Location Based Application Suite (Telecom)

2008

J.R.N.R.V. University Udaipur | Udaipur, RJ Master of Computer Application (M.C.A.): Computer Science Marks: 72.45%

2006

J.R.N.R.V. University Udaipur

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

11+ years of experience as QA engineer working on Automation and Manual Testing for multiple international enterprise clients in different domains delivering projects with excellent quality keeping customer satisfaction in mind. Seeking to utilize my knowledge and experience to excel further in Software Quality Assurance.

EXPERIENCE

10/2011 - Current

Lead QA Engineer Q3 Technologies Pvt Ltd | Jaipur Domain

- E-Commerce
- ERP/CRM
- IOT
- Travel and Logistics
- E-Learning

Soft Skills

- Coordinating and working with a large team sitting at different locations.
- Allocating work, guiding and mentoring new team members.
- Business/functional requirements gathering and participating in design discussions.
- Test planning and designing according to the consumer's point of view.
- Preparing and presenting QA status on weekly basis while working in Agile mode.
- Following complete STLC/SDLC.
- Supporting dev, test, pre-prod and production envs.

Clients/Projects

NIIT Digital - MS Dynamics 365 Integration (1 year)

- Domain: E-Commerce & ERP/CRM Finance & Operations
- Product: Managing Finance and Operations of consumer subscriptions via MS Dunamics 365 and integrating it with NIIT Digital web app.
- Lead/Sr QA Test Automation via Selenium, Core Java, Load Testing via App Logic, API Testing, Test Status, Plan, Design, Execution, Writing SQL Queries, and Mentor
- Tools/Servers: SaaS based Portal, BugNET, JIRA, SQL Server, Postman, Mongo DB, Eclipse, Selenium, Core java

NIIT Digital - Web Application (1 year)

• Domain: E-Commerce - Learning Science & Technology

Udaipur, RJ Post Graduate Diploma in Computer App(P.G.D.C.A): Computer Science Marks: 65%

- Product: Web app to manage consumer subscriptions for E-Learning.
- Lead/Sr QA Test Automation via Selenium, Load Testing, API Testing, Test Status, Plan, Design, Execution, Writing SQL Queries, and Mentor
- Tools/Servers: BugNET, JIRA, SQL Server, Postman, Mongo DB, Selenium, Core java

SREI - IQuippo - Marketplace (1 year)

- Domain: E-Commerce & ERP (auction, sell/purchase)
- Product: An auction platform for Vendors and Consumers for heavy construction equipments.
- Lead QA: Presenting App Demo, Mentor, Test Status, Plan, Design, Execution
- Tools/Servers: Backlog, Android/iOS Apps.

Reliance Telemetics - (2 years)

- Domain: IOT (Internet of Things)
- Product: Devices connecting vehicles and live tracking, web-app for Trip creation and assignment.
- Sr QA: Helping to pepare FRS document, API Testing, Test Status, Plan, Design, Execution
- Tools/Servers: IOT SaaS based Portal, Bugzilla, Mongo DB, MySQL, Hercules Simulator, Postman

ATC Transport - (6 months)

- Domain: Travel and Logistics
- Product: Transport web applications to support asset movement processes.
- Lead QA: Mentor, Test Status, Plan, Design, Execution.
- Tools/Servers: Bugzilla

EMax/DrugsRus/Mundi Pharma - (6 months)

- Domain: E-Commerce/E-Learning/Health Care
- Product: Multiple .
- Sr QA: Mentor, Test Status, Plan, Design, Execution.
- Tools/Servers: Bugzilla, Eclipse, Selenium, Core java

VGL - Auction Management System (5.5 years)

- Domain: E- Commerce & ERP
- Product: Multiple web applications for Admin and Consumers to sell Jewelleries in different countries.
- Sr QA: Automation Test via Cucumber and Selenium, Core java, Regression Testing, Database Testing, Load testing, Testing on Mobile and i-Pad, Test Status, Plan, Design, Execution.
- Tools/Servers: Issue Tracking System(ITS), SQL Server 2008, Site Core, Http Watch, IE Tester, Jmeter tool, Badboy tool

05/2010 - 08/2011

DCT Test Engineer

Wipro (STC Technologies Payroll) | Bangalore

Clients/Projects

GSK - Quality Risk Model System (1 Year)

- Domain: Health Care
- Product: Quality Risk Model System.
- DCT Test Engineer Testing database migration from sqlserver2000 to sqlserver2008, API Testing
- Tools/Servers: Quality Centre 9.2, SQL, MS-Office-Excel, sqlserver2000, sqlserver2008